[Music]
Hey,
woo.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day wherever
you are and uh welcome to episode 266 of
the Ask a Bijit show. I hope everybody
is doing great. Let us see who all is
there on the live stream. I can see
Shashank Koshik, Hunter, Hunter Kenway,
Alvin Rodriguez, U025250,
uh Lesie Baba, Aniketraati,
Manish Shishta, Kenil, Maklavin,
Yeshuan, Sudir, the magnificent Shuji,
Niha Sharma, Aolai, Global Citizen,
Arian Musk, Namaskar, Anudtas from
Assam, Hitan Shua,
Akash BA Latangi Suresh Malik Sayad Djam
from the US. Geopolitical Dub from the
from Indor anonymous scientist Bonjour
Rahul Himani from Mumbai. Uh Ready
always ready Shitan Shu freedom from
outcome from Canada. Sha Shah Raj Jimmy
Lee Wand Matram Latang Sur again uh who
else do we have? Uh Akash BA
uh who else do we have? Ra Rahul Dunak.
Uh we have ICBM, ICMBBS,
we have Chhatria Bal, thank you so much
for your contribution and thank you so
much for becoming a member. I really
appreciate that. I never ask anyone to
do that but you guys still do that. So
thank you so much. Thank you you in in
particular. Abhinav Kamani, thank you
very much for that. Who else do we have?
Who else do we have? We have Shah Raj.
We have Aayush Mishra Raggavoj
W Sharma Kumlist Manisha Kardo Mlvin
again Sai Sai Asank
Udai Rajawat Ankita Kachap Ashwini
Ranjan Kamal01
uh and so many other people. Priam J RJ
Prophet Bageshwar Army Abina 172
anonymous
IQ0000
and very complicated names I'm seeing.
So yeah, thank you so much all of you
for being here and then let's get going
with questions. This is a live chat
episode. I will take your questions from
the live chat. Uh no super chats today
either. Okay. So please go ahead.
Please, I request you all, please ask me
good questions. I like nothing more than
good questions. So, please ask good
questions and let's have a very
interesting 1-hour episode.
Okay, let us see.
Um,
Mr. Magnificent Nuji says, "What's the
ideal time to make public any classified
information and why?" So the right time
to make public any classified
information is when the classified
information is no longer sensitive or or
or u or it's or revealing it could still
be dangerous to uh the nation's
security. So when you reach a time where
revealing the information to the public
is no longer dangerous to the nation's
security, that's the right time to make
that classified information public.
That's the very simple um you know
um
logic behind that.
Okay, let us see. Let's have some
hopefully good questions.
Okay, Mlevin says, "I have noticed that
the the US and China might say that they
are enemies, but when it comes to
action, the US has supported China when
it counts. What do you think?" Well,
historically, if you look at if you go
back to the 20th century, the US is the
nation that was responsible for the the
rise of China. The US aided and omitted
and midwifed the why the rise of China.
The US came in Russia's way. The USSR
and China were adversaries after the
death of Stalin. Uh the they had these
clashes, border clashes because of
territorial dispute. The Usuri River
clashes. The USSR had decided to nuke
China. The US prevented that from
happening. then it helped China rise. So
they have done that historically. Even
today when they state that they are
enemies, they are adversaries. You find
both nations cooperating when it comes
to Pakistan and you find Pakistan
deliberately deliberately undermining
the collective interests of racks
in a way that actually strengthens the
US primacy globally. So yeah, you are
right that uh the US has supported China
when it counts, China still seems to be
supporting the US. I get the feel that
despite whatever the Chinese say, they
have this deep inferiority complex when
it comes to the US. The hero worship the
US. They they admire the US. They seek
to emulate the US. And the only thing
they seek is is US approval, right? I
mean, the Chinese believe they're
superior to everybody else. But when it
comes to to the US, the Chinese have an
inferiority complex despite whatever
they say and their actions
invariably
end up strengthening US primacy and
hedgemony
right what are the questions
um anonymous scientist says shouldn't
India deepen its ties with Israel
further as they can provide cutting edge
technology and the US seems to be their
wasal we
deepen our ties with Israel
pragmatically and practically.
We have to understand that Israel has
its own interests which are at times
divergent from India's interests and
obviously India also has its own
interests which are at times divergent
from Israel's interests but overall we
have a significantly broad u convergence
of interests on a large set of issues
and for these matters India should
certainly deepen its ties with Israel.
Yeah, you're right. Israel can provide
cutting edge technology to India,
whatever cutting edge technology it has
if it's open to doing that. And uh yeah,
you could say that the US seems to be an
Israeli vasal. But that that won't
really help India because that's that's
a bilateral issue between the US and
Israel and even if India tremendously
upgrades its partnership with Israel,
that won't change the India US dynamic.
I don't see that happening. But oral I
agree that we should um deepen our ties
with Israel.
Okay. The civilizational warrior says
you said that there are only five
sovereign nations in the world. US,
China, Russia, India, Israel.
Excuse me. What? US, China, Russia,
India and Israel. Okay, fine. Five. Uh
then what about nations like Singapore
and Switzerland? Well, if I said there
are only five sovereign states in the
world, it means that in my assessment,
Singapore and Switzerland are not
entirely sovereign nations. That's the
simple answer to your question.
Um,
uh, Devar of Worlds says, can we really
really achieve developed India with the
current chaotic system? No, we can't.
The only way we will have a properly
developed India, a genuine India, India
that genuinely achieves its full
potential, we need a different system.
This system won't take us there. Right?
So yeah, we can't achieve a fully
developed India with the current system.
Not possible.
Uh Malik says, what score will you give
according to the Cha Index to these
three major players in West Asia? Iran,
Israel, Saudi Arabia. considering the
12- day war. Uh the 12-day war hasn't
really changed the the dynamics the the
uh scores in my index because the scores
are based on a set of opensource
factors.
Um what are the factors? One is
your land area. Second is your
population. Third is your annual GDP,
the latest figures. Then you have
military budget.
Um then you have energy
self-sufficiently which is either one or
less than one even if you're a net
exporter I give it one so that it's
easier to calculate u then you have
number of nukes okay that matters then
you have power projection ability
capabilities how far can you project
power that's another factor I take into
consideration that essentially is how
many uh extra territorial bases do you
have military bases do you have and what
kind of land area or sea area do they
cover that sort of thing um and via
factors such as these.
So the current war that happened. So
this index is not something that is
meant to be uh modified every two weeks
or every month. It's something that is
meant to be to be updated once a year.
So this war of course if a significant
geopolitical upheaval happens that
genuinely reshapes uh the power the
balance of power in the region for
example the 2003 invasion of Iraq which
destroyed Iraq well then I would be
forced to significantly change the the
and recalculate the index in the middle
of the year but thus far that's not
happened this uh war in West Asia which
involved Iran Israel and with US
interferes it has not really changed
anything fundamentally.
Uh Israel hasn't got a victory. Iran
hasn't failed. Iran claims to have
succeeded in in a sense they have
succeeded in a sense they have won by
not being defeated. Um so nothing has
really changed.
So I will not change my scores at this
point in time. My my my scores will
remain the same.
Um
uh one Sharma says why is Donald Trump
so keen on ceasefires and what benefits
does he will he get from that? See my
friends
all foreign policy for any nation all
foreign policy is an extension of
domestic politics
especially when it comes to democracies.
If you're a democracy and you are the
leader of a country, let's say the
president or the prime minister, in that
case, well, you depend on the people's
approval and you depend on remaining
popular with the people in order to stay
in power, right? Because no matter how
far away it is, there is an election
coming coming at coming towards you.
There's an election down the horizon,
isn't it? Always.
So because of that it's very important
to remain super popular among your
people and that's why whatever foreign
policy decisions and actions you take
they are driven by your desire to remain
popular domestically. So all foreign
policy is an extension of domestic
policy and domestic politics. So why is
Donald Trump so keen on ceasefires?
Well, he wants to prove to the people
who voted for him that you made the
right choice. Donald Trump is the guy
make America great again. See see how
great the US is. We can go all over the
world and and create and and and mediate
ceasefires
and he will obviously make these
exaggerated claims like he the
completely false claim that he the he
mediated he mediated a ceasefire between
India and Pakistan and then over here it
looks like he actually did that when it
comes to the West Asia Asia ceasefire
between Israel and Iran. So he wants to
demonstrate to the world to to to his
voters that they have made the right
choice and then and he objectly
obviously has this objective this great
aim this great aspiration of going down
in history of leaving a legacy as the
greatest US president. I negotiated
ceasefires all over the world. I was the
greatest peacemaker and obviously he
wants to win a Nobel Prize. So these are
the benefits that Donald Trump seeks to
get.
Okay. Um
let us see.
Hitan shummeta says will NATO article 5
come into force if Israel attacks Turkey
someday? Erdogan administration the two
countries relationship deteriorated
considerably. Uh so there's a clause in
NATO one of the articles I don't know if
it's article four or five whichever it
is uh which is the the mutual defense
clause that if any one member of NATO is
attacked it is to be regarded it is to
be treated as a as an attack all
everybody else. So if any member state
of NATO is attacked all other members of
NATO are supposed to come to that
nation's defense immediately.
So with that understood,
what happens if Israel attacks Turkey?
Well,
well, Israel is a special nation. You
see, no matter what happens, so Israel
is not a member of NATO, first of all,
Turkey is, but what if Israel attacks
Turkey? I suppose the US will find ways
of not acting. Um,
obviously they'll be bound by the the
NATO treaty, but I don't think the US
will ever do anything that is
detrimental to Israeli interests. So, I
think in this scenario, the US
essentially prevents NATO from acting
against Israel. That's how I see it
happening.
Um,
Subagal says, "Are news headlines
scripted by the deep state to fool
experts worldwide?"
It's not meant to fool experts. It's
it's first of all I'm not talking about
the deep state here but it's true that
all news is propaganda. We know that I
mean if you have any sense you will
understand that all news outlets
they depend on funding.
Some of them they depend on advertising
which is fine but then the qu the user
experience is deteriorated because
there's too much advertising. You can
see some Indian news channels. They're
like that. But then they also get
funding from other sources. Maybe that's
a major part of the funding. Maybe some
channels get full funding from some some
sources. The question is who's funding
them? When you have various sources
funding you, you are constrained to
operate and act in a way that is not
detrimental to your funders interests
and actually is positive for the for the
funders which is good for the funders's
interest, right? You to further their
interests. So if somebody owns you, you
will end up serving them. That's as
simple as it gets. And all news outlets
across the world are owned by somebody
or the other. either collectively or
partially or whatever.
So that tells us that all news is
actually narrative. All news headlines
are essentially propaganda. Subtle
propaganda at times, overt propaganda at
times. Some of this could be funded by
China. Some of this could be funded by
the US. Some of this could be funded by
Russia. None of it is funded by India
because India doesn't play this game. We
are good guys, right? So the objective
of doing this is to create narratives
and propagate narratives.
And narratives are meant to fool the
general population, the 99.9% people of
the world. They can't fool experts, the
0.1%. Those can't be fooled. But as long
as every news outlet is repeating the
same lies, nobody will pay attention to
the experts. That's how it goes. All
right.
Okay.
Ananta Chandak says
uh could can Starlink contain guns and
with their access on India can they wipe
out a place in an hour? Would something
like this happen? What should we do if
we have to counter it? No. Starlink
can't contain guns
because of the physics of the thing. So
even if you could, you know, fire a gun
in space, which you can't,
can you fire a gun in space? I have
never thought of that. It's a chemical
reaction. Does it need oxygen? I suppose
it needs oxygen
or does it not need oxygen? I have to
think about it. I'm not sure what's the
chemistry is, what the chemistry is when
it comes to gunpowder. Does it operate
without oxygen? I doubt if it operates
without oxygen. So if it doesn't ignite
without oxygen, then you can't fire a
gun in space. But even if you could fire
a gun in space, hypothetically, there's
a recoil. And these Starling satellites
aren't very large. They aren't very
large in mass. So they'll they will
suffer from recoils and they'll get
dislodged out of position. That doesn't
work. That's terrible for the satellite.
Then it's then it can be used only once
to fire one bullet. So because of the
physics, it's simply not possible for
this to happen. Okay. So then what is
the use of Starlink? Starling obviously
is is something that provides
space-based internet which can be used
to undermine the sovereignty of a nation
and I've discussed that in the past.
I'll not go into it right now. For
example, let me anyway tell you. Let's
say for example you have Pakistani
terrorists who have infiltrated into
Kashmir or Mauist terrorists some
somewhere in the red belt or some some
uh uh
for example some riers in some city in
India or maybe um cookie terrorists in
Manipur or whatever. So wherever they
have you have some bad situation the
Indian government can impose a phone and
internet blacked out blackout for maybe
24 48 hours or whatever it is you can do
it but if Starlink is coming in the
terrorists or the riers or whoever can
simply use Starlink devices to
coordinate with with each other and outf
fox the Indian authorities so that
directly compromises India sovereignty
that's why we should not have it so that
is the first threat from threat from
Starink apart from that I suspect that
Starling satellites will have very
sophisticated uh surveillance equipment
which essentially means that each
Starling satellite could be a spy
satellite which could give the US real
time intelligence about what is
happening on the ground. So I think
that's the utility of Starling not guns.
Uh Jim Lee says, "Can we as a cold
calculation swap Akai Chin for Arunachal
Pradesh to reach a temporary peace with
the Chinese and demarcate the border?
Something like the Moloto of Ribbentrop
Pact." Well, you have given us a nice
historical precedent. The Moloto of
Ribbentrop Pact. Now ask yourself, Jimmy
Lee, how long did the Molo of Ribbentrop
Pact last?
Molotov kept his end of the bargain, but
the Ribbentrop did not. and Germany
ended up launching operation Barbar Roa.
So that pact did not last. It was simply
a placeholder and Stalin himself knew
that it's going to happen sooner or
later, right? Everyone knew it was just
a temporary thing. What's the point of a
temporary pact
and why would you give up Arunachal
Pradesh
and the people who live there? They are
Indians. How can you do that to our
people? Think about it. Even it's a cold
calculation. Why? Why? Why? Why? Why do
that?
Axai chain. Okay, you get excited in
return, but there's nobody living there
essentially. So, you give up a
significant percentage of a population
for a land where where there's almost
nobody living. Isn't that a stab in the
back for the people of Arunachal
Pradesh? How can anybody do it? So, this
is this doesn't make sense from from my
perspective. Okay, it's a good uh
academic discussion.
uh but no we want to do that.
Shiraawastasi says why is new advanced
technology always used in the military
first before any other sector because
national security is paramount and lots
of technology has multiple uses newly
used technologies and you can't allow
that to leak into the public sector
because once it becomes public then
other nations can steal that technology
and use it before you for their
military. So you always keep it secret.
You always use it for the military first
and only when you have mastered it and
you're beyond anybody else can you
slowly release it into into the public
domain. That sort of thing.
Um
R says to which physicists are you
petrified of in terms of intelligence?
How good is Edward Whitten? Edward
Whitten is fantastic.
Who am I petrified of in terms of
intelligence? Well, I don't mean to
sound arrogant, but I'm not petrified of
anybody in terms of intelligence.
Okay. Um,
let's see what this is. Hitanchu says,
"We have come a long way. Back when
American planes landed during operations
in Iraq, it quietly shifted the
trajectory for foreign policy towards
the US. From there to here, times have
changed. Is it true?
uh we may have allowed US aircraft to
perhaps potentially refuel in India
during operations in Iraq possibly. I
don't remember what was the case but
maybe we did. Uh
today I'm not sure if uh US aircraft
have such uh privileges in India. We
obviously don't have any foreign
military bases on our soil because that
would be a violation of our sovereignty.
We are no one's vasal. We are sovereign.
So we don't have any foreign bases on
our soil. We sometimes have military
exercises exercises with the
coordinations with the west with the US
in which case we can temporarily give
access to our air bases for refueling
and other purposes. Right now we have an
F-35 of the UK which is squatting on our
territory on uh on an airport in
somewhere in the south that's owned by
the Adani group right it's it's
squatting there for I think more than a
week now that's unusual and so on but
overall yes times have changed um our
policy is much more clear now as to what
we will allow what we will not allow and
yeah that's that indicates that we are
very very uh clear we have we have clear
red lines It's about our sovereignty.
Okay.
Nature vibe uh etc. says, "Can't
Starlink operate without our
permission?" Starlink can operate
without our permission.
Yes. So even if we don't give permission
to Elon Musk, it's possible that he
could turn off the beams of the
satellite
when they pass over India
turn them on. So which means that
Starlink could be beamed into India even
if India does not give permission like
he has said
with respect to some other country that
we will do what we want and you can
shake your fist at the sky. He has said
that right? So that's that's his
attitude. That's his actual attitude.
That's who he who he really is. So he he
can certainly switch on
the Starlink
uh beaming into India. The question is
will anybody be able to receive that
without Starlink receivers.
So as long as we don't give permission,
we can. So as long as that we have a
situation where India has not given
permission to operate Starlink in India,
it means that we will not allow Starlink
receivers to be sold in India or to be
possessed by anybody in India. Make it
illegal as long as Starling doesn't have
per permission which means that there
will be essentially next to none next to
zero Starlink receivers in India unless
they are illegally smuggled into India.
Right? So even if Elon Musk decides to
beam his internet into India, as long as
we ensure there are no Starlink
receivers inside India, uh it will be
very hard for people to actually use
Starlink unless you find back doors and
workarounds or whatever which I suppose
could be possible if you are very
techsavvy possibly but overall it can't
operate even if uh uh Elon Musk decides
to as long as we don't allow Starlink
receivers to be used in India.
Anonymous scientist says would China
become friendlier to India if it became
democratic? Well, China will never
become democratic and even if it becomes
democratic, it will have its own
interests. And this is um this is a
hypothetical question. So what's the
point? Uh Haran Gokul says why is India
singled out for castism even though many
nations had cast systems and castlike
constructs? Look, that's a good
question.
It's because
yeah there is Hindu phobia and the west
seeks to uh single out India because it
it sees India as a threat and you are
okay so what is this cast system thing
right what's this cast system well there
was no cast system in India we had the
vernati system which was a very
intricate system of uh division of labor
and you had so many
clans and lineages ages of people of
families who were occupied in very
specific
um occupations
for generations
and they would me make sure that nobody
else would could take up the profession
they would safeguard it zealously
zealously not jealously but zealously
right
and this was an accepted practice in
India so that's why we had so many jatis
and verna and all that jati verna It was
very complicated. The British could not
understand it. Their little minds could
not get it. That's why they superimposed
the forecasts on India.
Now if you go back to the time of uh the
Morian era, you had a Greek ambassador
in Patipra which was our capital 2 and a
half thousand years ago. The guy's name
was Mastanis. He wrote a report about
India, a pretty tactical report about
India, strategic report.
And this report was called indika. It
doesn't survive. But there are other
Greek texts that survive that have
referred to the indika. So we know
partially what wrote about and he wrote
about Indian society and so on so forth.
And he said that Indian society was
divided into seven classes not cast
seven classes. Uh and I don't remember
what the various classes were but you
had uh trades people and priests and
warriors and seven classes not four
seven. So during the Morian times during
the time of uh Vishnagupta Chanaka and
Chandra Gupta Gummoria and Ashok the
great and so on you had seven classes in
Indian society not four.
Um
and look any functioning society
is an organized society. It has division
of labor and when you have division of
labor you have classes and these these
constructs that organically
form over time.
And the sign of a disorganized society
is that it has no division of labor.
It's it's chaotic. And if you try that
in a company, if you try to make the the
the janitor equal to the CEO and make
the CEO do the janitor's work and the
janitor do the CEO's work, that company
is going to crash and burn in no time.
And the same goes for any nation.
And uh India's system was never
discriminatory.
It was never discriminatory until India
came under foreign occupation when
India's culture and uh India's
India society could no longer function
the way it had evolved to function
organically for thousands of years. So
imagine this situation okay I suppose
many of you must have read or watched
Harry Potter. So in Harry Potter in
Hogwarts there is a cast system
four casts.
What is it? Uh, Gryffindor, Slytherin,
Ravenclaw, and Huffle Hufflepuff.
But it's not a hereditary cast system.
There is a sorting hat. So, whenever a
new student reaches Hogwarts, they have
to go through the sorting hat process.
And the hat decides which cast they go
into. Right now imagine that there's a
disaster and Lord Voldemort
emerges victorious and he destroys the
sorting hat and he decrees that from now
onwards nobody will be sorted into any
cast. Then people
will be forced to somehow keep the
tradition alive which means that they
will say okay now that we no longer have
the sorting hat our kids will now now on
take the cast of their parents so it
becomes hereditary because of the
foreign imposition by Voldemort because
the society can no longer function the
way it was supposed to function so it's
forced to take recordourse to
suboptimical suboptimal measures
do you See what happens here. Voldemort
destroys the way the society functions.
So the society somehow wants to keep
some tradition its tradition alive in
some shape or form
and that's why it resorts to making it
hereditary now instead of making it
making it happen through the sorting
hat. And that's how these defects and
deficiencies enter society because the
cast was supposed to be determined by
the sorting hat not by who what parents
you have. And that's that's an analogy
of kind of very simplistic analogy of
what happened in India after the Turk
occupation of India and the later uh
European occupation of India.
That's how things became rigid and maybe
there was some oppression at some point
in time only in the past thousand years
not before that. Please understand that
uh when India was under foreign
management you blame the managers and
the leadership not the not the workers
right in any company when the company
crashes uh that sort of thing. And yeah,
there are other countries that also have
had terribly oppressive systems. Good
God.
A thousand years ago in England, at
least one out of 10 persons wore a
copper collar. They were slaves. One out
of 10 people were slaves in England. But
nobody says England was oppressive.
H nobody says that
they they had this gong farmers in
England. gong farmers, people who were
allowed to come out only at night and in
England they used to throw
sewage and excretita on the streets.
England was a disgustingly smelly place.
This is all part of the historical
record. They don't highlight it, but
it's there. Look it up.
So, there was something there was a
profession called gong farmers. Gong
farmers.
These folks were only allowed to come
out at night and their job was to come
with buckets and scoop up
the human excretita on the streets of
England and dispose of it somewhere and
those people were not allowed to mix
with society. Isn't this a horrible form
of discrimination and oppression? In
France, you had people called people
called the kag c a g- o ts who were
similarly discriminated against. In
Japan, you have the Burakumin.
Once again, even today, they face
discrimination. Even today, the
Burakumin people face discrimination.
You had this all across the world. We
have never been that sort of thing. But
we are singled out for this. And the
worst thing is that our own people are
brainwashed into believing that we were
evil. We are a bad society. We have a
bad civilization and culture. That's
what your teachers in your textbooks do
to you.
Anyhow,
anyhow.
Um,
well, I'm glad you like it, sir. Harry
Potter analogy is excellent to explain
about castism. Well, I'm I'm glad that
helps see things in perspective,
hopefully.
Um,
Amisha Mashara says, "What's the
significance of Axiom mission 4?" I
haven't really been pay paying attention
to Axiom mission 4 because of all the
other stuff that's happening in the
world right now. The world is like on
the brink of something or the other
right now. But yeah, we have this Axiom
mission mission 4 which was launched by
I think the space space X Dragon capsule
and you have an Indian astronaut who's
gone into space. Well, okay, good, good.
I forget his name but I think he has
reached orbit if not the International
Space Station by now possibly.
And all right. So I'll be happy when we
launch our astronauts on our own rockets
in into our own space station. This is
Space X launching in Indian to the
International Space Station. The
vehicle, the launch vehicle is American.
The space station is Western.
Well, it makes no difference to me. It's
not some big cause for celebration. As
far as I am concerned, I don't know what
the significance is. I haven't paid
attention to it. I don't feel like
paying attention to it. I'll be
interested when we launch our own spa,
you know, human spaceflight mission with
our own our own rocket, our own
spacecraft and eventually we will have
our own space station. That's what will
interest me. That's what get me excited.
This unfortunately, I'm sorry to say,
doesn't really excite me.
Right.
Yeah. I will not discuss about what
other people are saying about something.
It's not important what the what other
people are saying. Um
uh Sha Shazi Shash. Okay. Whatever the
name is, sorry. The question is, what's
your opinion on the criticisms that our
diplomatic relationships are broken like
never before in recent years? Well, the
opposition parties their job is to
criticize the government. But hopefully
they should criticize. There should be
valid valid critic criticism. See, in
recent years, everything has changed.
The whole world is turning upside down.
Everything is different today. Things no
longer work the way they worked even 5
years ago. Forget about 10, 20 years
ago. In the past, the world was stable.
You could see geopolitical change
happening only when you looked at the
world decade upon decade. Right now the
geopolitical situation is changing every
week.
So the world was a different place two
weeks ago than it's than it was today
than it is today. I mean what today is
what June 27.
Two weeks ago June 10 there was no West
Asia war, no West Asia crisis. Iran's
nuclear program was fine. Iran and the
US were negotiating about the nuclear
deal and all and look at where we are
today. A whole different world. Things
are changing so fast. The world is re
realigning very fast. Multipolarity and
by bipolar bifurcation of the world
order and so much more happening right
and India is growing. India is rising
and now India is being seen as a
potential future threat by lots of
countries. Because of that we are under
severe pressure from multiple fronts.
This is a sign of our success not our
failure. If we had remained mediocre
like Dr. Manm Singh said that we have no
ambition of being a major power then we
would have had stable relations with
everybody. Nobody would have considered
us a threat and that's why everybody
would have stable relations with us
including China including the US. But
today they are all unhappy with us
because we are growing.
This is a sign of our success not our
failure. That's why they are leveraging
Pakistan. That's why that's why they've
done a regime change in Bangladesh. East
Pakistan. That's why they are trying to
encircle India. That's why China is
helping Pakistan and Pakistan is sharing
um you know battlefield intelligence
with with China. That's why China wants
to sell the J35 to Pakistan. That's why
China and Pakistan and Bangladesh are
doing this trilateral arrangement for
the first time ever. That's why the US
is uh siding with Pakistan over India.
That's why Trump is investing in
Pakistan. That's why the US is operating
the Nurhan air base. That's why that's
why Pakistan likely has US nuclear
weapons, not its own nuclear weapons.
All of this is a sign of our success.
But it's very counterintuitive to
understand that. But that is what it is.
It's not a sign of our failure. It's a
sign of our success. And the more we
succeed, the more troubles we'll face.
But that's the price you have to pay if
you want to reach your full potential.
Okay.
Um,
I'm trying to find some good questions.
Trying to find some good questions.
Yeah, it's hard to find good questions.
H,
okay, let's just take some questions
because I'm not able to find like
questions that excite me. Anyway, please
why why don't you folks ask good
questions? Please ask questions that are
relevant to what's happening in the
world today and questions that will be
valuable for everybody to hear an answer
to. Please do that. Anyway, let's see
this. Isn't water also a resource like
oil? Of course, it is. So, why can't we
sell water to Pakistan and Bangladesh in
instead of giving it for free?
Look, water oil doesn't flow on the
surface of the of the planet like water,
right? Like rivers. Rivers
flow but oil is underground so we can
extract oil and then sell it. But water
is something that flows freely and for
us to stop it we have to
we have to build dams and all that. I
mean it should be obvious, right?
It's not like or our water exists in
packages.
Okay, let's see if some there's some
more interesting questions.
Nilles says, "Will India industrialize
in the next 5 years?" India is in the
process of re-industrializing. We were
the first industrialized society. The
first fully industrialized society 5,000
years ago. We are in the process then we
were de-industrialized by the British
fully. Now we are in the process of
reindustrializing. We will be further
industrialized in 5 years. Uh I don't
know what is fully industrialized. What
it means? The west says that it is fully
industrialized. Whatever. Um India is in
the process of re-industrializing. So
India will be significantly further
ahead in the next 5 years.
Um,
what is the age of the sun according to
the sun itself? Well, I have never had a
conversation with the sun. That's why I
have not been able to get
the sun's perspective on what its age is
according to itself. From the best that
I know, it's about 4.5 billion years
old. But that's my perspective. And that
that's the perspective of these little
humans who live on the planet. We don't
know the perspective of the of the sun
because as far as I know, no human has
successfully communicated with the sun.
We're not aware if the sun is conscious
or if it can communicate or if it wishes
to communicate and so on.
Uh Akash says Japan abandoned its dharma
during the Maji era to gain power. Must
bat do the same or can it rise as a
civilizational superpower while staying
true to dharma? First of all, let us
stop using this word superpower. This is
the Indian obsession with status
entitles
to hell with the term vishwaguru. to
hell with this term superpower. Be
practical. Be pragmatic. My dear
friends, my dear viewers, forget about
these titles. Forget about the status.
We are a nation that was for the past
1,000 years on its knees. Then we were
made to crawl on all fours by the
British. Now we are standing up again.
We are in the process of standing up and
starting to walk.
Before we can fly, we have to start to
walk. Then we can start jogging. Then we
can start running. Then we can start
sprinting. Then we can perhaps start
think of flying.
So forget about being a superpower.
Forget about that right now for the next
50 years. This superpower obsession is
just annoying. But coming to the
question, Japan did abandon Dharma. Uh
that's what happened as a consequence of
the Maji restoration. The samuras were
killed off. They were the guardians of
dharma in Japan. Uh and Japan became a
completely westernized society
full of the cruelty of the west. They
embraced it. They rejected dharma.
The maji restoration attempted to
eradicate Buddhism which came packaged
with Hinduism from Japan. It failed. uh
but the Japanese uh government and armed
forces became entirely non-harmic and
that led Japan to commit all kinds of
horrific atrocities which nobody can
deny
in Korea in Manuria
in China in Nanjing for example good God
and so on and that eventually also you
could say to some extent contributed to
the fall of Japan and the
continuing occupation of Japan by the
Americans.
So if Bat wants to rise not let's say as
a superpower but as a great power let's
say let's let's do it step by step.
Let's say Barat wants to rise to the
fullest extent of its potential which
means that Barat will once again be the
world's largest economy. Let's stop at
stop at that for now. Okay, we certainly
have historically always been the
largest economy. So that is something we
should aspire to in the next 50 years
let's say. So do we have to abandon
dharma to to achieve that? I don't think
so. I think it will be horrific for us
to abandon dharma. That's the one thing
we have going for ourselves. That's the
one thing that we have that was given to
us by our ancestors 10,000 years ago.
Something that all our ancestors have
continued. And if we give it up, it will
be the greatest betrayal of all. will
betray hundreds of generations of of our
ancestors.
What it's like the what the Christians
call a deal with the devil. The devil
will give you whatever you want but in
exchange for that you have to sell your
soul to the devil. Uh I would never do
that. So I would say bat should never
give up its dharma. Barat should learn
from its history and from its dharmic
heritage.
Learn how to succeed.
Learn how to win. Learn how to conquer.
Shri Krishna tells you all in the Bhagat
Gita and and beyond. Uh so learn from
the past. Uh we don't have to abandon
dharma. We have to stay true to dharma.
Okay.
Arian says, "Doesn't China realize that
Pakistan is a conflict of interest with
respect to the US and a symbiotic rel
relationship with India wouldn't be
would be better for all parties
involved?" I think China has eyes and
ears. Yeah,
China has eyes and ears. China is very
well aware, please, more than me, more
than all of us, what relationship the
Chinese, the Pakistanis have with the
US.
What the Chinese are doing with Pakistan
is supplementary to what the US is doing
with China with Pakistan.
And yeah, see for example, the Chinese
are are possibly on the verge of selling
J35 fighter planes to Pakistan. And the
question you may ask is that if China
sells this fifth generation fighter
plane to Pakistan, will the Americans
not get their hands on it and reverse
engineer all the all the Chinese
technology and then will China not
become vulnerable when China has to
fight the US for potentially in the
future? Well, the J35s they will send to
Pakistan will be
downgraded, dumbed down J35s. They'll be
the so-called export versions, not the
full versions. They will not have the
latest cutting edge edge technology.
They'll be dumbed down versions of the
J35 and they'll fail just like the other
of Chinese systems failed.
Okay,
so China knows what it's doing. It's
playing a very strategic game.
Um,
will a symbiotic relationship with India
be better for China?
Well, I suppose it would be, but China
sees itself as very different from
India. China sees itself as rightfully
as the more powerful nation,
significantly more powerful, two and a
half times more powerful in terms of
hard power. So they say that India
should not be our our partner. India
should be our vasal and India is not our
equal. So we can't deal with India as an
equal. Uh maybe they're right in saying
so, maybe they are stupid in saying so.
Only time will tell. But that is the
approach they have chosen for the
matter.
Uh okay.
Uh
okay. Mlevin says, "What's the key
difference between Zoran?" Zhan is that
okay that new guy and Vive that helped
Zoran win both are of Indian origin is
it religion or the or the political
party that they represent.
So this new fella Zran Mani
uh he has I I believe won the mayoral
election in New York. So he is going to
be the mayor of New York City.
So what what does this development
represent first of all?
So from the Anglo perspective, from the
perspective of the Anglo,
there's the Atlantic and there's the two
sides of the Atlantic. There's the
there's east of the Atlantic, which is
England and the UK, and there's west of
the Atlantic, which is the US.
So here's the deal, friends. And by the
way, here's the deal. East of the
Atlantic,
you have the mayor of London, Sadi Khan.
And now west of the Atlantic you have
the
upcoming mayor of New York City Zran
Mamadani. London is the financial
capital financial center of the UK and
New York City is essentially the
financial center of the US. So you see
they are
kind of balancing things out. So now
you're going to have a US version an
American version of Sadik Khan in their
financial center. Both are of Indian
origin. Saladi Khan is a Pakistani
origin if I'm not mistaken but the same
thing Indian origin. Yeah, because there
was no Pakistan 80 years ago. Uh and it
was all India. So yeah, both are of
Indian origin. Uh what's the key
difference between Zorhan and Vive?
Uh Zoran is a is a standard issue lefty.
Um he has no actual agenda of his own.
He just wants to come to power and
prominence and he will
they will sell his soul if required. So
he will do whatever his political
masters tell him to do. It's just like
Sadi Khan and as a consequence they will
get all kinds of benefits and stuff. So
he's a typical American lefty.
He is not a Republican. He's a Democrat.
Uh he's a recent immigrant if I'm not
mistaken. And the key difference is that
uh Vive
Vivec is a grassroots guy. He's a
self-made billionaire.
He's a very highly intelligent person.
Vivec and that's what annoys white
Americans. A guy who had nothing when he
was born. Very humble background,
regular Indian background. s becomes a
billionaire through his own work and is
super intelligent and dares to run for
the presidency of the US. Okay, that's
Vive. On the other hand, you have Zuran
Mani
who has no qualities of his own. He's a
Nepo child, Nepo baby. His mommy and
daddy were people of of stature. His
mommy is this leftist filmmaker Mirana
na fake Mallayali person actually
Punjabi Miran nayer and his daddy is
some fellow who is some some academic
somewhere
Indian origin from Uganda that sort of
thing. So, Zoran
has benefited from the fact that his
parents are both reasonably well placed
in society and his mom helped him with
his campaign, the movies and the the and
and the campaign advertisements, the
shooting and the filming of that and all
that. His mom is a filmmaker so so she
knows how to make really high quality
films. So, all of that helped. So, Vive
has risen on his own. Zoran is a Nepo
child. Nepotistic child. That's a
significant difference. But because he's
part of the left, he's positioned and
portrayed in a certain way as being not
which is not offensive to the to the US
white population. And so that's that's
kind of the the key differences that I
can see at this point. I have actually
not looked into this Zan person at all.
I have no interest in the guy. Um but
maybe I'll have to look into it in the
future. Let's see.
Uh
let's see what other questions we have.
Questions that I've hopefully not taken
a 100 times in the past.
Let us see. Let us see.
Okay. This I'm sure I've not taken in
the past. Suas says
u the recent Air India crash into a
building raises doubts about 2611 or did
the US hire engineers from Saudi Arabia
and spend 10 trillion to dismantle the
twin towers on a serious note what's
your opinion okay so I have not raised
this question but there have been people
in the US who have been raising this
question uh because of the very
unfortunate and tragic accident that
happened in Ahmedabad the Air India
which still isn't resolved I mean it's
still a mystery how did it happen but
we'll not go into that. So the aircraft
which was a Dreamlininer, Boeing
Dreamlininer,
it uh crashed into a building. Very
tragic thing and the building still
stands. So this big giant aircraft flies
into a building and the building is
intact. I mean it's not intact but it's
standing. It did not collapse. On the
other hand, we have these uh aircraft
that crashed into the World Trade Center
towers and the World Trade Center towers
went down.
Does it raise questions about 2611?
Possibly. Possibly.
Yeah. Um
but we also have to understand the
differences. The aircraft that were
flown into the twin towers, they were
flying at full speed essentially. They
were trying to accelerate as they hit
the towers. Okay. And the air in the
aircraft was decelerating. It was going
it was it was losing lift. So the
momentum would be very different.
Okay. MV squ mass times velocity
squared. The momentum would be very
different. I suppose the momentum of the
twin towers aircraft would have been pro
possibly significantly higher than the
Air India flight that that flew into a
building into a hostile building or
whatever it was. Uh that's that. But
even if the momentum is so high, the
twin towers were made of very highly
reinforced steel and steel cages all
over the place. And there are still
questions as to how they went down, but
I'll not go into those questions. But
yeah, um maybe it's something we should
perhaps uh kind of investigate perhaps.
Okay,
Chiraawasti says, "Why don't we have
strategic bombers like the B2 and
Russian bombers? Is it because we are
more of a defensive power or they're
than an aggressive power?" It's because
historically we have had no ambition of
being a great power during the Nairovian
time during the 20th century after the
20th century until Mr. Modi came to
power we have had no ambition. Mr. Manm
Singh had famously said that India has
no ambition of being a great power. we
are happy being in South Asia and
remaining where we are that sort of
thing. So when you have no ambition when
you have prime minister like Mr. Moraji
Desai who had no ambition from what it
looks like then why would we why would
you invest in these expensive platforms
why would you either buy them or or have
your scientists and engineers develop
them why right so that's why we don't
have the strategic strategic bombers the
B2 is very advanced the Russians have
plenty of high quality strategic bombers
that date back to the USSR days but they
are still very relevant and very useful
today right uh it's because we have our
leaders have never had any ambition
We are a gigantic nation and our
interests, our national interests
require that we invest in all kinds of
platforms including strategic bombers
which are very long range bombers that
can that can drop very significant
quantities of uh explosive of of bombs
but we don't have it. It's unfortunate.
It makes sense to have strategic bombers
but these are expensive and we have
never developed them. If today we need
them, we would have most likely we'll
have to purchase them from probably
Russia. It's because of our leaders
having no ambition. That's why we are in
the situation.
Okay.
Um
Adv
Abdut says the US Congress had a hearing
yesterday on the UAP UFO issue. Okay.
They almost agreed on the existence of
nonhuman non-human intelligence
technology and contact. What's my views?
I am super skeptical.
There's no question about the fact that
these phenomena exist.
Last year uh during the end of Mr.
Biden's presidency, there was this UFO
outbreak in the US, especially over New
Jersey, New York, etc. UFOs all over the
place. Now they've decided to call them
UAPs. They've rebranded the thing UAPs.
So you had all kinds of UAPs, UFOs
across the US or sightings on live news
with the city in the background. They
could see a whole bunch of UFOs flying
around on live news. So you can't deny
the phenomenon.
And you had these orb orblike UFOs which
are just like balls of light. You had
aircraft like UFOs with blinking lights
and all that. You had all kinds of
different kinds of UFOs. You even had an
aircraft like UFO
transforming into an orblike UFO.
So what I think the situation is is that
the US most likely has advanced
technological programs
and these
technologies
are what people consider to be UFOs. And
I believe that after Mr. Trump came to
power, his press secretary, she said, I
believe that this was US technology. It
was not UFOs or or aliens. What we saw
in in dur during the last quarter of
last year,
it was US drones. I think that's what
she said. Um, so I believe I am of the
opinion that it's most likely. I think
there are two scenarios. Scenario A and
scenario B. In my opinion, scenario A
has 99.9%
likelihood of being true and that is
that this is just advanced US technology
that is secret from the world very
advanced technology but human
technology. So that is scenario A in my
opinion it has a 99.9%
chance of being true. Scenario B has a
0.1% chance of being true in my opinion
and that is that this is aliens who are
visiting the planet. Okay. So that has
in my opinion 0.1% chance of being true.
I am not ruling it out. Okay. But I
think it's very unlikely and maybe
there's a combination of scenario A and
scenario B. That's also a possibility.
Uh so I am super skeptical. I don't
trust these claims easily. I think that
it's most likely US technology and
there's a very small likelihood that
there you may have aliens uh present in
the PL in our atmosphere perhaps.
Uh
let's take a couple more questions.
Shoubam says, "Can India invade
Bangladesh to protect Hindus?" Today we
we have the news that came out that we
expressed strong concern
over the unilateral attacks on Iran by
the US and Israel,
unprovoked attacks, right? We express
strong concern about this on on the
bricks platform. So if we express strong
concern about this, can we then attack
Bangladesh unprovoked? Even if
Bangladesh is killing its Hindus, the
West will say that there's no
provocation. It never happened because
it's not being reported in the Western
media.
So even if this is happening, India is
not in a position to invade Bangladesh.
India is not in a position to do that.
It would be great if we could do that
and save the Hindus.
But at this point in time, forget about
the Hindus of Bangladesh, my friends.
What about the Hindus of Banipur? What
about the Hindus in certain other parts
of India? What about the Kashmiri Hindus
who are still not able to go back to
Kashmir?
What about the Hindus of our own country
within India
who are being terrorized?
What about that? Let's first let's first
take care of our Hindus, right? Then
we'll think about Hindus from of outside
India.
Okay.
Okay. This is a good question. This will
be the final question of the day. How do
space probes, says Amisha, how do they
travel through the asteroid belt? They
travel straight through the asteroid
belt. Why is that? Because the asteroid
belt is mostly empty space.
when we look at depictions. Okay, let's
take a look at depictions of the
asteroid belt. Let's go to Google. Okay,
what does the asteroid belt look like?
Let's see
that. This is how artists will depict
the asteroid belt
uh as this. This is a depiction of the
asteroid belt. This is a depiction of
the asteroid belt.
This is another depiction. It looks so
crowded.
Look here. It looks so crowded.
Look at this. So much rocks, debris,
dust.
Look at this. So crowded. But in
reality,
the asteroid belt is almost empty.
The average distance between any two
asteroids will be several million
kilometers.
You may have increased dust over there.
So you will need to take some
precautions like shielding and all just
in case. But overall, there's no issue
flying through the asteroid belt. So
that's how you do it. Don't worry about
it. Okay, with that we have come to the
end of today's live stream.
All right, I'll I'll end it over here.
Thank you so much for all your questions
and I will have a longer live stream, a
regular ask a widget qu session
tomorrow. Um maybe with super chat,
maybe not. We will see about that. And
uh Suresh is saying that Google maps has
not been opened the show. Well, yeah,
sometimes it happens. So hopefully it'll
open tomorrow. So, thank you so much for
all your questions. Take care. Keep
asking questions. Keep raising your
standards. And I'll see you hopefully
tomorrow. I I look forward to seeing you
tomorrow, 8:00 p.m. for tomorrow's live
stream. Thank you. Bye-bye.